smiffys.com 2016-05-16

# Privacy Policy

**1.**|  **Introduction**  
|   
1.1| 

This privacy policy (the " **Privacy Policy** ") shall apply to use of [www.smiffys.com](http://www.smiffys.com/) (" **Website** "). Use of the Website will be deemed agreement to the terms of this Privacy Policy by a user (" **User** "). The Website is operated by RH Smith & Son (Wigmakers) Ltd trading as Smiffy's (" **Smiffy's** "), a limited company registered in England whose registered office is situated at Peckett Plaza, Gainsborough Business Park, Caldicott Drive, Gainsborough, Lincolnshire DN21 1FJ.  
  
 **2.**| Collection and storage of personal information  
|   
2.1| Use of the Website shall constitute consent from Users to the collection and use of personal information in accordance with these Terms and Conditions. Smiffy's is the data controller for the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998.  
2.2| Smiffy's may collect and process personal information about Users such as the following:  
| (a)| information (including, without limitation, name, email address and telephone number) provided by completing forms on the Website, including when ordering any product or service through the Website; and  
| (b)| reporting problems or submitting queries or comments regarding the Website or its content or any other such communication sent to Smiffy's.  
2.3| Smiffy's may not be able to provide Users with specific services if Users should choose to withhold requested information, but Users are not under an obligation to provide any such information.  
2.4| Information that Users submit via the Website is sent to and stored on secure servers located in the United Kingdom.  
2.5| Where a User is a trade customer we will also collect and process information at the point a trade account is created, including business name and contact details, payment information and account log-in details (such as user password and an answer to a  seleted security question).  
 **3.**| Cookies  
|   
3.1| 

The Website uses cookies to store and collect certain information. Cookies are small text files which are transferred to Users' hard drives to store and sometimes track information about Users. This enables Smiffy's to deliver a better and more personalised service to Users. Although cookies enable Smiffy's to identify Users' computers, cookies used by Smiffy's do not personally identify Users. Certain cookies we use last only for the duration of the Users' web session and expire when the browser is closed. Other cookies are used to remember Users when they return to the Website and last for longer. Smiffy's uses cookies to:  
  
| (a)| store Users' preferences;  
| (b)| estimate Smiffy's audience size and usage patterns;  
| (c)| recognise Users who return to the Website;  
| (d)| allow Users to navigate the Website more quickly and easily;  
| (e)| update and improve the Website; and/or  
| (f)| control how often Users view similar online advertisements.  
| | In addition we may use or allow the use of  web beacons/pixel gifs on the Website. These are small image files that may be placed by us or by third parties in respect of Users visits to the Website or within the body of Smiffy’s newsletters so that Smiffy’s or third parties can understand which parts of the Website are visited or whether particular content is of interest.  
3.2| Smiffy's does not use cookies to store the credit or debit card details of Users.  
3.3| Users may refuse to accept cookies by activating the relevant setting on their browser that enables Users to refuse the acceptance of cookies. However, Users that take such action may not be able to take full advantage of the Website. Users can also learn more about cookies by visiting www.allaboutcookies.org which includes useful further information on cookies and how to block cookies using different types of browser.

For more information about the specific cookies served through this website and how to restrict or block certain of these cookies Click here  
  
 **4.**| Use of personal information  
4.1| Smiffy's will use the information Users provide to:  
| (a)| enable Smiffy's to process Users' orders and to provide Users with the services and information offered through the Website and which are requested by Users;  
| (b)| send Users information that Smiffy's considers they may find useful or which Users have requested from Smiffy's, including information about Smiffy's products and services or those of carefully chosen third parties, provided that Users have not indicated their objection to being contacted for such purposes;  
| (c)| allow, with Users' consent, carefully chosen third parties to send Users information directly that they may find useful in relation to their products and services, provided that Users have not indicated their objection to being contacted for these purposes;  
| (d)| audit the downloading of data from the Website;  
| (e)| identify visitors to the Website;  
| (f)| improve the content and/or layout of the pages of the Website and customise the pages for Users;  
| (g)| undertake research on our Users' demographics; and/or  
| (h)| verify and undertake financial transactions concerning payments made by Users online.  
| (i)| We may first conduct credit checks with reputable credit agencies on users who apply to be trade customers in order to establish a trading account and a record of this check may be retained on the agencies’ files.  
4.2| Users can request not to be contacted by Smiffy's with information in relation to Smiffy's products and services or those of third parties or to share their details with third parties, either at the point such information is collected on the Website (by checking or un-checking (as directed) the relevant box) or by following the unsubscribe instructions on any communications sent to Users. In addition, Users can exercise the right at any time by [Contacting Smiffy's](http://www.smiffys.com/Info/t-contactus).  
 **5.**| Disclosure of personal information  
5.1| Smiffy's reserves the right, from time to time, to disclose Users' personal information to any of its affiliates, agents or contractors in connection with providing the services offered through the Website, analysing data, complying with requests for information, receiving and sending communications, updating marketing lists, processing transactions, providing support services or in other tasks. Use of Users' personal information by Smiffy's agents and contractors shall not exceed the extent necessary to perform their functions.  
5.2| Users agree that any personal information held by Smiffy's may be transferred to a re-organised entity or third party in the event that Smiffy's undergoes re-organisation or is acquired by a third party.  
5.3| Smiffy's may disclose Users' personal information if Smiffy's believes that disclosure is necessary to protect the Website or the rights, property or personal safety of any person or prevent fraud or cyber crime, or if otherwise required by law.  
 **6.**| Information security  
| Smiffy's considers that the security of Users' personal information is of the utmost importance. Smiffy's has put in place security measures to attempt to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of personal information under Smiffy's' control. Smiffy's carries out reviews of its security and privacy policies periodically and implements enhancements when necessary. Access to personal information is only available to authorised personnel. However, Users acknowledge that the internet as a medium for the submission of information is never entirely secure. Smiffy's is unable to guarantee the security of information submitted by Users through the Website whilst it is in transit over the internet and any such submission is at Users' own risk.  
 **7.**| General  
7.1| You are entitled by law to a copy of the personal information Smiffy's holds about you and to inform Smiffy's of any inaccuracies in such information. If you wish to request a copy of your personal information or inform Smiffy's of any inaccuracies, you may do so by [Contacting Smiffy's](http://www.smiffys.com/Info/t-contactus). Smiffy's is entitled to charge a nominal fee (not exceeding £10) to cover its costs in providing you with a copy of your personal information.  
7.2| Smiffy's reserves the right to vary this Privacy Policy from time to time. This Privacy Policy was last updated on 29 March 2012.  
 **8.**| Contacting Smiffy's  
| Any queries or comments in relation to to this Privacy Policy or any requests concerning personal information should be directed to Smiffy's by email to sales@smiffys.com, or alternatively by writing to Smiffy's at:  
Smiffy's   
Peckett Plaza  
Gainsborough Business Park  
Caldicott Drive  
Gainsborough  
Lincolnshire DN21 1FJ  
 **a.**| Our cookies  
| Smiffys.com uses cookies with the aim of improving the user experience. They facilitate common features users expect such as persistent login's and also provide some other features which improve the performance of Smiffys.com.  
| |  **Cookie name**|  **Purpose**|  **More Information**  
---|---|---  
ASP.NET_SessionId| We use this cookie to link your use of Smiffys.com with temporary data sorted on our servers; this cookie is a random character string. With this cookie we attempt to make Smiffys.com more user friendly, by providing functionality such as remembering preferences.| Duration / Expires:  
When the browser is closed  
ASPDNSFGUID| We use this cookie to link your use of Smiffys.com with temporary data sorted on our servers; this cookie is a random character string. With this cookie we attempt to make Smiffys.com more user friendly, by providing functionality such as persistent login.| Duration / Expires:  
When the browser is closed  
IsTheme|  This cookie is used to store a particular preference relating to the themes and categories on the website. It is used to remember if you last accessed the themes or categories on the left column, and expand the relevant group.| Duration / Expires:  
When the browser is closed  
SkinID| This cookie is used to identify the layout and styling of Smiffys.com.| Duration / Expires:  
1 Year  
StatsView| This cookie is used to identify the layout and styling of Smiffys.com.| Duration / Expires:  
1 Year  
themeslistitems| We use this cookie to store information about the themes, with the aim of improving the performance of Smiffys.com.| Duration / Expires:  
When the browser is closed  
themesmenucurrent| We use this cookie to store information about the themes, with the aim of improving the performance of Smiffys.com.| Duration / Expires:  
When the browser is closed  
CategoryFilterID| This cookie is used to remember a filter preference.| Duration / Expires:  
1 Year  
DistributorFilterID| This cookie is used to remember a filter preference.| Duration / Expires:  
1 Year  
GenreFilterID| This cookie is used to remember a filter preference.| Duration / Expires:  
1 Year  
ManufacturerFilterID| This cookie is used to remember a filter preference.| Duration / Expires:  
1 Year  
ProductFilterID| This cookie is used to remember a filter preference.| Duration / Expires:  
1 Year  
SectionFilterID| This cookie is used to remember a filter preference.| Duration / Expires:  
1 Year  
VectorFilterID| This cookie is used to remember a filter preference.| Duration / Expires:  
1 Year  
IsProductPage| This cookie is used mark when you view a product page.| Duration / Expires:  
261 seconds  
LastViewedEntityInstanceID| This cookie is used to store the ID of the entity you last viewed, to improve performance and create useful features such as the breadcrumb navigation.| Duration / Expires:  
1 day 261 seconds  
LastViewedEntityInstanceName| This cookie is used to store the name of the entity you last viewed, to improve performance and create useful features such as the breadcrumb navigation.| Duration / Expires:  
1 day 261 seconds  
LastViewedEntityName| This cookie is used to store the type name of the entity you last viewed, to improve performance and create useful features such as the breadcrumb navigation.| Duration / Expires:  
1 day 261 seconds  
SiteDisclaimerAccepted| This cookie is used to indicate whether a user has accept the site disclaimer.| Duration / Expires:  
When the browser is closed  
 **b.**| Third party cookies  
| Cookies are also set by third parties on the Website or these are set by us using the third parties cookie code. More information about cookies placed by third parties and how to restrict or block their cookies can be accessed by following the link to their website.  
| |  **Cookie name**|  **Purpose**|  **More Information**  
---|---|---  
Google Analytics| Google Analytics is a web analytics service which uses cookies to evaluate your use of this website. Google Analytics sets or updates cookies only to collect data required for this reporting. Google Analytics cookies do not collect personal data about your activity.

These cookies are used to determine your visit sessions, identify anonymised unique visitors, identify the source of visits and navigation paths and set custom variables depending on actions taken on the site.

| Persistent Duration:   
2 years 6 months  
<https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

More information about cookies from Google and Cookie time frames:   
<http://code.google.com/apis/analytics/docs/concepts/gaConceptsCookies.html>  
  
Twitter.com| Where our Website includes a Twitter feed, Twitter may use both session cookies and persistent cookies to improve their service including understanding user interaction, monitor aggregate usage and web traffic routing.| Persistent:   
2 years  
<http://twitter.com/privacy>
